# **Muhammad Zunair Khan**

# FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

zunairkhan811@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

Full-stack developer with 1300+ hours of coding and collaboration experience with international remote developers. Ability to learn new languages and manage the team effectively to deliver a quality product on time. Enhanced UI/UX and created engaging interactions using front-end technologies like Reactjs and Ruby on Rails with Postgres database for Backend.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, Reactis, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, Postgresql

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, npm, Jest, respec-rails, capybara, bullet, CanCanCan, Devise, Bootstrap5, Sass, Webpack,

Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Render, Netlify, Github-Pages

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Code Reviewing, Communication

## **EXPERIENCE**

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full Stack Web Developer

Remote Jan 2023 – Present

<u>Hotel Booking</u> — Pair programming project, A user can reserve and unreserve hotels, and only the authorized user can add and delete hotels.

Built with: Ruby on Rails as the backend, and Reactjs as Front-end.

<u>React Stock</u> — Stocks-Data is presented using Stocks API, and the details of every stock are shown when the user clicks on the specific stock, and the project is completed using React-Redux.

• Built with: React-Redux, and Fetch API.

Movies Web App — A movie web application that retrieves movies and TV shows from an API and updates them within the app. Users can add comments and like their favorite titles.

Built with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Webpack, and Fetch API.

Webly Education Project — This is a web application that provides details to get online education.

Built with: HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) Feb 2023 - Jan 2024

- Mentored 10+ junior web developers, and provided technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed 10+ improvements to code organization for improving code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips to 10+ junior developers on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.
- Provided code reviews to my coding partners.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Jan 2023 – Jan 2024

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Spent time engaging in peer-to-peer online interactions and building relationships with individuals from diverse communities and cultures.